All righty.
Welcome to the project.
So I'm very excited about this one.
We are creating a music player.
I've always been interested in music players on computers for the past 20 years or so.
Going back to my Winamp days, shout out to anybody that knows what Winamp is.
And today we're going to be making our own music player within our HDMI, LCROSS and JavaScript.
We can see that we are showing some album artwork here.
We have the title of the song.
We have the artists of the song.
We have the current time.
We have the total duration of the song.
We have a play button here.
We have a next button and a previous button will go over the functionality.
Now, one by one.
So of course, we want to be able to play a song and pause a song as well.
We want to be able to go to the next song.
So you can see that the album artwork has changed.
And the title has changed.
And the duration of the song has changed.
And you can see as we play that the current time is increasing.
And if we play this song, we can actually scrub through by clicking on the progress bar.
And we can also use the next to loop through our songs indefinitely.
And the previous to go back through our songs and definitely so we'll always have music playing.
And now previous.
OK.
Perfect.
So we have an idea of the core functionality that we trying to achieve.
Now we're going to break it down one at a time and get everything done.
All right.
Let's get started.