All righty, so to start with, there is a template zip file within the course that you should be downloading.
And once you've unzipped it, you'll have a folder like this.
And what I would suggest you do is rename it.
So I'm going to remove the template part and just have it called Music Dasch player, just to show that
I'm working on the project now and we're going to open this folder up within Visual Studio Code.
OK, so you can see in our sidebar here that we have two extra folders in addition to our three standard
files.
The first one is an image folder.
So these are just images that I pulled from on Splash.
I'm going to provide a link to the creator of these images within the CSX file.
And I've also included MP three files in a music folder.
You'll notice that they have the same names.
That's to make it easier in our JavaScript to call these items.
And you might notice that these songs actually have my name on them.
So these are actually music files that I have produced.
I've been making music since I was 16 years old and I thought it'd be cool to throw some into the project.
All right.
So let's open up our H.T. email, our CSX and our JavaScript files.
And then I'm going to hide the sidebar just to make some more room on our page here.
All right.
So the first thing we're gonna do is just launch our project with our live server extension.
OK, so we can see that we already have a background color on our body.
You can feel free to change this.
But the overall theme I'm going for with this project is a modern craze style.
So therefore, I've included some CSX within the template to make things a little bit easier so we can
focus more on the JavaScript.
So let's jump back to our H.T. mill and start actually building out our project.
So the first thing that we're going to include is we're going to actually make a div that's going to
contain our entire player so that we have the ability to move it around on the page so we can use the
auto complete within visual studio code.
So div dot player, dash container and press enter.
And that gives us a div with the class player container.
And within this we're going to comment on the title.
We're going to add in our song properties here.
So the first thing is we're going to create a div with the class of AMG dash container for our image
and we're going to put an image inside of that.
And the source for this image will be our image folder slash.
And then you can see it auto completes for us.
We're gonna go with the first one, Jacinto Dash one dot jpeg, of course, for your project.
If you want to change the audio and the images, you can feel free to.
You just want to put in whatever names will correspond to the files you've included.
And for our all tech, we're just going to put in album art.
And below this, we're going to add in the title.
For our songs, we're going to have an H two and we're going to add an I.D. of title.
And I'm going to just put in the information that I know it is for the first song.
You do the same thing, just put in whatever the song name is that you have in this case.
This is the example.
I can use the hashtag here to add an idea quicker way so I can have an H three now with the idea of
artist.
So this is going to be a little bit smaller and I have the artist here and the last thing I'm going
to add is the actual audio element itself, which is of course very important.
So we can type audio and press tab.
The source is going to be our music folder.
And again, we're gonna go with the first one.
Jacinto Desh one, MP three.
And I'm going to take it a step further.
And I'm temporarily going to add controls just so that we can actually see the element on the page.
All right.
So let's save that and check it out.
OK.
So we have our image here.
And if we scroll down, we have our title.
We have our artist.
And we even have our audio element here.
So the good thing about using controls is that it actually enables us to use the audio.
So you can see that we have a play pause button.
We have the current time.
We have the duration.
These are things that we are going to recreate ourselves using custom elements that are going to provide
the same information.
Let's get back to the styling, though.
The next thing that is a huge thing that can be changed and customized is, of course, the fonts.
So we're going to use Google fonts for that because it's the quickest, easiest way to do it.
So on the Web site, you can choose any font that you would like.
I have a specific font in mind, so I'm going to search for it.
It's called Spartan.
So whenever you click on a font that you would like, it goes into a detail view for that font.
And I know that I actually want two different font weights here.
So I want the regular swinging to click select this style.
And I also want a bold version as well.
So I'm going to click select this style as well.
So I want two different font weights here to add it to the project.
We're just gonna click embed and we specifically want the import statement and we're just going to copy
this.
And we're going to jump back into our CSX.
So, you see, this is the credit for the images that I'm using here.
Feel free to check out his work.
He has a lot of great stuff on UN Splash and right below that.
I'm going to add in our import statement for our font.
And then within the body can see we already have some styling here.
I'm going to add in the font family and it's going to be Spartan comma.
I'm going to add sun dash surf just as a backup in case it doesn't load.
OK, so let's save that.
Jump back and check it out.
OK.
I would say that that font looks a whole lot better.
Awesome.
Next, we're gonna move on to actually styling our player container.
So you can see right now that the image is as big as it wants to be.
But we want the image to be a certain size and we want the container that's holding that image to also
be much smaller than this currently is.
So let's jump back to our CSX and right below our body.
We're going to start styling for our player container.
So this was the first d'Hiv that we created.
We're going to start with giving it a certain size.
So I'm going to give it a height of five hundred pixels and I'm going to give it a width of 400 pixels.
So the reason I want it to be 400 is because most smartphones, large smartphones, I should say.
So I have the S 20 plus, for example, their screen width is just a little bit over 400 pixels.
So this will be able to fit on that screen without any kind of media queries.
OK.
And the next thing is we want to create a background color.
For this, so the next thing is we want to have a background color.
That's just a little bit lighter than our body background color.
So I'm actually in a copy this again.
You can choose whatever colors you would like.
But what I'm gonna do is I'm actually going to use something that's very handy within Visual Studio
Code.
And that is the color picker.
So you see, if I hover over it, it opens up the color picker and I can just kind of decide to pick
a lighter color.
So we want it to be lighter.
I think that's a good color there.
OK, perfect.
So keep in mind, you can do a similar thing.
You can select a background color and use the color picker to just pick a lighter version.
All right.
So let's save that and check it out.
OK.
So we can see that we have our container here.
We see our image is still way too big.
But I like the way that this gray works with this gray.
OK.
Now I'm going to show you two properties that you can use that will instantly make whatever you're working
on.
Look more modern.
So the first one is border radius.
So this is having the ability to add rounded corners to any element.
So in this case, I'm going to add a border radius of 20 pixels.
So rounded corners is very important.
And it's a trend that has been continuing for a number of years and shows no signs of letting up.
So you can see just by rounding that corner, it looks a lot more modern.
The second thing is using box shadow.
So it provides a shadow to elements.
In this case, our d'Hiv.
And that allows it to look like the element itself is kind of floating on the page.
So there are a couple different values we're going to need to enter here.
The first one is horizontal offset.
So that means a shadow is going to go left or right of the element.
We actually don't want any of that.
We just want a vertical shadow.
So just a shadow directly below the object.
So the vertical offset, we're gonna set at 15 pixels and the next property is referred to as Blur.
And this is the amount of opacity added to the shadow.
So if you had a value of zero here, it would make it a solid color.
Of course, we don't want that.
We want it to be very subtle.
So we're gonna give that a big value of 30 pixels.
The next value is the spread value, which determines how far out from the element.
The shadow is, again, because we want it to be subtle.
We're gonna set that at five pixels so it's not too far away from the object.
The very last thing is we're gonna set the color and we're gonna use an RGV a value and we're gonna
use black.
So zero zero zero.
And then the A stands for Alpha, which can also be thought of as opacity.
And we're gonna make that zero point three.
So that makes it.
30 percent of the black color.
So it's kind of See-Through.
All right.
So let's save that and check it out.
OK, so you see what I mean about the shadow here.
It looks like it's kind of coming off the page, but it's very, very subtle.
I think that looks a whole lot better.
I hope that you feel the same way about that.
And I hope that you enjoyed this quick tip.
Next, we're going to start trying to tame our image here.
Next thing is we're going to try to tame our image here and we're going to use an approach that would
allow you to put in an image of any size and have it fit properly.
So this is through using something called object fit.
So you can see that we have a whitespace here of a rectangle, but we see that this image does not fill
this space.
If we switch to fill, we can see that it fills the space, but it distorts the image.
We're actually going to use this option object fit cover, which allows it to fill the space but not
distort the image.
So that's what will allow you to put in any size image and it will just fill the space properly.
OK, so let's jump to our see, assess and figure that out.
OK, so you can see that we already have some styling within our image container.
We're going to need now to set the height and width.
So first, I'm going to make it a square.
So I'm just going to have a height of three hundred pixels and a width of 300 pixels.
Of course, I want it to be smaller than the width of our overall container.
And you can see that it'll have 50 pixels on the left and then 50 pixels on the right.
That's how we're going to center it within our player.
Container.
And the next thing is below our image container.
We're gonna actually need to do some styling for the image within our image container.
So let's do that.
Below image container.
And we want to target the image element inside.
And we're going to set this height to be 100 percent.
And the with to be 100 percent as well, because the container is setting the hard pixel value and we're
just using this to have the image fill the container.
And, of course, we can add the object fit cover as well.
Like I just explained.
And we also want to add border radius and box shadow.
So I'll actually copy this.
But this time, we want the box shadow to be a little bit more subtle.
So instead of 15 pixels for a vertical offset, it's going gonna change it to five.
OK, so let's save that.
And check it out.
OK, maybe you want that to be a little bit darker.
So you know what, I can increase this from zero point three to zero point five.
OK.
So that's looking really, really nice.
Perfect.
But let's have a look at the mobile view and see what that looks like.
OK, so we can see that we're in the mobile view for an iPhone X and we can see that our container is
not fitting because the width of an iPhone is three hundred and seventy five pixels and the width of
our player container is 400 pixels.
So we're gonna need to change that value in order to make that work.
So let's jump back to our C assess.
And if we scroll to the bottom, this is always where you want your media queries because you want it
to override anything else above.
You want this to have the last word.
And we're gonna target our player container and we're just going to change the width to be ninety five.
V.
W.
So that means ninety five percent of the screen with meaning that it'll have 2.5 percent of the screen
with margin on the left and right side.
And you can see that specifically.
I already made this media query for iPhone vertical and the max width is three hundred and seventy six
pixels.
So anything less than that will be controlled by this media query.
Of course, our iPhones are three hundred and seventy five pixels.
Let's jump back and check that out.
OK.
Perfect.
So everything is now fitting in our iPhone size.
Awesome.
If you have any issues with this.
Sometimes a dev tools a little bit finicky.
You might have to click responsive and then go back down to the size that you want.
In this case, also, the audio element controls might cause some issues.
So try just deleting this element and it'll show that the layout is working fine.
Don't worry about deleting this because this actually won't be part of the UI of our final project.
All right.
So everything's looking really great so far for our layout.
Let's take a break here and we'll build out the rest of the UI in the next one.
I'll see you then.
Bye for now.