All righty, so let's finish up our UI and that's going to be adding our own progress, bar and button
controls.
So we're gonna start with the progress bar.
So let's jump back over to our code in our H.T. Amelle.
We're going to create this underneath our song.
We're going to add in title here, progress.
And we're gonna start with a div with the class of progress, stasch container and the I.D. as well
of progress stasch container.
And inside of this, we're gonna create another div with the class of progress and the idea of progress.
So this container is going to be what holds our progress bar.
And this is the actual bar that's gonna change sizes as we're going through the song.
And we also are going to have a div that is going to hold our duration as well as our current time.
So we're gonna make Span's for that and we're gonna provide an I.D..
Of current dash time, and for right now, we're just going to hardcoded.
So it'll be zero zero zero and we're going to create another span.
And this one is going to be for our duration.
And this one I know off the top of my head that it's two minutes and six seconds.
You can even actually see that within our audio controls here.
So we're just hard coding that value.
OK.
So let's save that and check it out.
So you can see that all of the styling work is done for us.
That's nice.
And we have our project container here and we have our actual progress here.
And you know what?
Let's actually hide the controls because we want to actually build out the rest of our UI and see how
it's actually going to look.
So let's do that.
Let's just get rid of these controls for now.
So the next time we'll control our audio will be through our JavaScript.
And if we jump into the sea, assess here, we can see that we do have.
Our styling.
All done for our progress container.
You can see that we're using border radius again on both of these.
This is the background color.
This is the dark color.
And you can see that we already have a width here of sixty six percent.
So this is going to be changed dynamically in our JavaScript when our song is playing to show exactly
how far through the song we are.
But for now, it's just a static value of sixty six percent.
OK, so let's save that and jump back.
OK, so that's more what our UI is actually going to look like.
And you can see we have a space here that is a space for our button controls.
So let's jump into that next.
Back in the code, we can see at the top of our H.
T Amelle, if we use our word wrap Alte Z, we can see that we're already importing font awesome into
our project.
So you don't need to worry about that part.
But if you want to know how to add different icons, I'm just going to go back briefly to the font awesome
Web site and I'll provide this link within the course.
But you can see that we have a number of different icons here and you can search.
So let's say that I want to search for a play button.
This is the button that we're gonna use.
But let's say that you wanted to use a play circle button instead.
You could click on that.
So any icon that you click on, you can see that you can actually copy the H.
T Amelle for the icon.
And that's how you would add it into your project.
OK, so let's jump back to our HD, UML and make our buttons.
So we're gonna go below our progress section here.
We're going to comment out another title.
And this is going to be for our controls and we're going to start by creating a div again that will
act as a parent element.
This allows us to really control the placement on the page.
And we're going to go ahead and make each of our icons here.
So we're going to use AI is our element.
And we're going to use the classes of F.A.A. s.
So that stands for fun.
Awesome.
Solid.
And then I can add another class by adding another period.
In this case, we're going to do our previous button first.
And that is F.A.A. dash backward.
And we're also going to give it an I.D. so we can keep stacking these an I.D. of previous.
But I'm just gonna put Prešov and we can press enter there.
And lastly, I'm actually going to also add a title.
So that when we hover over it, we can see exactly the functionality of that icon.
OK, so I can paste this twice more.
And we're going to change this.
This is going to be our play button.
So just f a play.
I'm actually gonna give this another class main dash button because I want this button to be bigger
than the other two.
And and change the idea to play.
And the title of this.
Well, to play.
And the last button is going to be forward.
So we're just going to change that to forward and we're going to change this next.
And our title will also be next.
OK, so let's save that.
And next, we're going to jump into the CSX.
So if we scroll down, we can see that again, we have some styling included already, including the
position of our player controls and the width and everything.
And you can see that we're targeting the FAA s class.
So that's the main class.
It's on all three of our icons.
And we're controlling the size with font Dasch size because essentially it acts as a font, even though
it's an icon.
But there are two very specific classes that we want to have if we are going to use an icon as a button.
So if we just jump over right now to our project, we can see that these look great.
But when I hover over them, there's no sign that I can actually do anything with them.
So what we're gonna do first is we're gonna add in curser pointer.
You can see it auto completes if I press tab.
And the next thing we're going to add is user select none.
You can see if we press tab twice, it will auto complete.
So that's to prevent it from being selected like any other font could be selected.
OK, so let's save that and check it out.
So I was talking about this is like user select because this is a font.
We don't want that to happen.
And so you can see that when we hover over now, not only do we have our titles, which is great, we
have the cursor change to a glove, just like it would with a regular button.
It's still maybe could be a little more clear when we're hovering over it that it's ready to be clicked.
And we can do that by changing the color of the button.
And we can do that in a very quick way.
So below this, we're going to target our F ace class and we're gonna use a pseudo class hover.
So this class will only be initiated when it's being hovered over with the mouse and we're gonna use
filter brightness and 80 percent.
So that means that our buttons will become 20 percent darker as they're being hovered over.
So let's jump back and check that out.
OK, so I think that that's a little bit more of a dramatic difference when we're hovering over the
button.
Perfect.
Feels a lot more interactive.
All right.
So that's pretty much it for our UI in the next one.
We'll get started on our functionality.
I've seen that one.
Bye for now.