All righty, so we have a lot of different functionality to get to, but we're going to start with the
most basic first, and that is our play pause functionality.
You might remember that when we had our controls for our audio within here, though, we already had
that ability to play and pause our audio track.
We're going to need to transfer that ability to our custom icon here.
So first, we're gonna look at a resource that talks about audio and video dom elements.
You can see that we have different methods, properties and events.
And in this case, we don't have to scroll very far because we're interested in the methods here.
We can see that we have a play method and we have a pause method.
That's pretty self-explanatory.
So we're going to need to trigger these on our audio element.
So let's jump back to our code.
We're gonna start in our JavaScript and we're going to need to target.
A few different things, so we're going to target our audio element because we want to be able to control
that.
And we're also going to be targeting our buttons because that's what's going to allow us to actually
control.
So you can see we have ideas for these, but the audio element doesn't have an I.D. So that's because
we can reference this in different way.
Let's make a constant.
Called music for audio element, and this is going to be equal to document query selector.
The bottom line here, I'll scroll down and press enter.
And so this allows us to select an element or a class or an I.D., anything we want to pass in there.
So in this case, because we only have one audio element, we can use this to select that.
And below that, we're going to create constants for our buttons.
So we're gonna call Prešov B10 for our button.
And that's going to equal document dot get element by I.D..
And this is are Prešov I.D. that we added on their.
And I'm just going to actually copy and paste this to more times, and in this case, we can use our
select, which is our command DS or control DS, depending on if you're Mac or Windows.
And you can see we've selected both, there's a cursor on each.
And I'm going to use that to change that, to play.
And I'm going to do the same thing with this and change that to.
All right, perfect.
So we're done selecting our elements.
Next, we're gonna need to make functions for our play pause functionality.
We're going to do that below.
So we're going to start by commenting on a title.
Play an organ and create a function called play song.
We're going to make this different than just play, because we already have that method within the audio
element itself.
Now we're going to target the constant four audio element, which we're calling music, and we're just
going to pass in the method of play.
And we're gonna do a similar thing with our paws.
So I'm actually going to copy this paste below and change this.
I'll highlight both of these and change them at once.
OK.
And they're both paws.
Next, we're going to need to trigger play if the music is paused or pause if the music is playing already.
So to do that, we're gonna need to add in a boolean that we're gonna set within each of these functions
to show whether it is playing or not.
So we're gonna commentate a title above.
Check if playing.
And we're going to let is playing.
It's the name of our boolean equal false.
And when we're playing a song.
Is playing is going to be true.
When we are paused, is playing is going to be equal to.
False.
And when we first load the page is playing is going to be false because it won't start playing until
you hit the play button.
Next, we're gonna go over our event listener functionality.
So based on whether is playing is true or false, we're gonna want to launch the opposite function.
If it's playing, we want to pause.
If it's we want to play, we can accomplish this with a ternary operator.
So this is similar to an if statement.
For those of you unfamiliar.
This is the syntax.
We're gonna provide a condition in this case.
We want to check if the is playing boolean is true or false.
And then we have an expression if true.
And then we have Colen and then expression if false.
In this case, we're gonna run a certain function.
If this is true and a different function if it's false.
So let's set that up.
We're going to add an event listener below our functions.
And we'll call it the play or pause event listener.
And on our play button, we're going to add an event listener and we're going to add a click event,
comma, and we're going to use an arrow function instead of making a separate function for this.
So we're going to have brackets, equal sign creator arrow here.
We can actually add our ternary operator on the same line.
So we're going to add in another bracket here for that operator is playing and then space questionmark.
So if it's true now, we want to pause the song and then brackets to show that we're launching the function
and then we're gonna have a colon and then we're gonna have play song, the other function, and we're
going to have another set of brackets for that function.
And we'll put a semicolon at the end here.
So just to clarify, these brackets are for that function.
This other bracket is for the ternary operator.
And this last bracket is for the entire event listener.
All right.
So let's save that and we can finally check it out.
OK, awesome.
We have some music playing.
That is great.
The one thing you might notice, though, is that the play button stayed a play button.
We actually want the play button to turn into a pause button if the music's playing and vice versa.
So we'll need to add that within our code.
So if we go into our play functionality first, below are is playing bullion.
We are going to target our play button.
Class list and we're going to replace this allows us to do this on one line instead of an add and remove
on two separate lines.
And we want to replace the class F a dash play.
That's what it will start out with when the page loads with F.A. Dash pause.
So when it's playing, we want to show the pause icon and vice versa.
We'll copy that and we'll put that into our pores.
But we're gonna flip these, so we're gonna replace.
The pause with the play icon in this case and the last thing we'll do is we actually want to change
the title.
So you remember that we set the title of play.
We can do that by using the set attribute method.
And in this, we're going to set the title attribute, comma, and then we're gonna set it with pause
so that when we hover over, it will also say pause and won't say play over the pause icon and we'll
copy that.
Pasted in here.
And this time we want the title to be play.
All right, so let's save that and check it out.
OK, so we can see that we have our play icon here and it says Play.
And if we click on it, we can see that we had our Porres icon there.
That's awesome.
And if we hover over the pause icon.
We can see that it's his paws.
All right, awesome.
We have our play and paws functionality sorted out in the next one.
We're going to start looking at our previous and next functionality.
I'll see in that one.
Bye for now.